{
    "id": "9b70b30a014f40369e1f44f3c5437ded",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "In some of the villages they still ............................ electricity.",
            "description": "We do not use the word miss to say that somebody hasn’t got something.",
            "answers": [
                "lack",
                "miss",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "fa5e1bd95324403d90339d02870af68b"
        },
        {
            "question": "She threw a glass at me, but .................................",
            "description": "Lost is not used with this meaning. To miss is to fail to contact somebody.",
            "answers": [
                "missed",
                "lacked",
                "lost"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d058f712e9324ca7a28ab1cdc948d746"
        },
        {
            "question": "If we don’t hurry we will ................................ the train.",
            "description": "Lost is not used with this meaning. To miss is to fail to contact somebody.",
            "answers": [
                "lose",
                "miss",
                "lack"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6fb35678b9a3462199d2c902dedaf1b5"
        },
        {
            "question": "When did you realize that the bag was ....................................?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "missing",
                "lost",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "d52c79ec27474e61878d9e365d4bde11"
        },
        {
            "question": "The kitchen ought to .................................... these days.",
            "description": "Somebody has to paint the kitchen. So we use a passive infinitive here.",
            "answers": [
                "paint",
                "be painted",
                "be painting"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "256d1b5063be468ca9628b1749b73586"
        },
        {
            "question": "................................ university students have to borrow money these days.",
            "description": "We use ‘more’ before a noun without a determiner.",
            "answers": [
                "More",
                "More of",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "dcbc06e8ad7b462fbe63d092909f58c6"
        },
        {
            "question": "You ................................ be Anna’s sister – you look just like her.",
            "description": "We can use must to express the conclusion that something is certain.",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "must",
                "will"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "dfe93fc15a50469884120f0740888b37"
        },
        {
            "question": "Do we need .............................. seats on the train?",
            "description": "When need is used as an ordinary verb, it is followed by a to-infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "reserve",
                "to reserve",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f9876b76cbbc49aa91e28187390df67b"
        },
        {
            "question": "You seldom work on Saturdays, .................................?",
            "description": "We use an affirmative tag after negative expressions like seldom, hardly or rarely.",
            "answers": [
                "do you",
                "don't you",
                "did you"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "fc6bb895e6874c02b872ca74eacdc6ab"
        },
        {
            "question": "................................... quick results when you learn a foreign language.",
            "description": "We make negative imperatives with do not + infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "Expect not",
                "Do not expect",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f31ae3e76f524b399ad29fa9bf0c4759"
        },
        {
            "question": "There is little point in asking him, ..............................?",
            "description": "Clauses with little and few are followed by affirmative question tags.",
            "answers": [
                "is there",
                "isn't there",
                "does there"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "0094c0fa51e245c49e024398288de89c"
        },
        {
            "question": "He has few reasons to quit, ...............................?",
            "description": "Clauses with little and few are followed by affirmative question tags.",
            "answers": [
                "hasn't he",
                "has he",
                "does he"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a05832959166468b8bfee6c0fc777e01"
        }
    ]
}